wp.io 2013-12-26

# Privacy & Cookie Policy | FreelanceWP

Effective as of September 2012

## wp.io Privacy Statement

wp.io has created this privacy statement (“Statement”) in order to demonstrate our commitment to customer privacy. Privacy on the wp.io web site (the “Site”) is of great importance to us. Because we gather important information from our visitors and customers, we have established this Statement as a means to communicate our information gathering and dissemination practices. We reserve the right to change this Statement and will provide notification of the change at least thirty (30) business days prior to the change taking effect.

## Collected Information

We require customers who register to use the services offered on our Site (collectively, the “Service”) to give us contact information, such as their name, company name, address, phone number, and e-mail address, and financial qualification and billing information, such as billing name and address, credit card number, and the number of users within the organisation that will be using the Service. At the time you express interest in attaining additional information, or when you register for the Service, we may also ask for additional personal information, such as title, department name, fax number, or additional company information, such as annual revenues, number of employees, or industry. Customers can opt out of providing this additional information by not entering it when asked. Customers can update or remove their personal information at any time by logging into the Website and editing their Personal Information within Settings. Customers can view their updated profile to confirm their edits have been made.

wp.io uses the information that we collect to set up the Service for individuals and their organisations. We may also use the information to contact customers to further discuss customer interest in our company, the Service that we provide, and to send information regarding our company or partners, such as promotions and events. Customers are invited to receive an email newsletter by providing an email address. Customer email addresses and any personal customer information will not be distributed or shared with third parties. Customers can opt out of being contacted by us, or receiving such information from us, at any time by sending an email to contact at wp.io.com. Separately, customers are also asked to provide an email address when registering for the Service, in order to receive a username and password. We may also email information regarding updates to the Service or company, and will send a Customer Newsletter. Again, email will not be distributed or shared and customers can opt out of receiving any communication by emailing contact at wp.io.com at the time it is distributed, or at the time any customer registers for the Service.

Except as we explicitly state at the time we request information, or as provided for in the wp.io Master Subscription Agreement, we do not disclose to third parties the information provided. All financial and billing information that we collect through the Site is used solely to check the qualifications of prospective customers and to bill for the Service. This billing information is not used by wp.io for marketing or promotional purposes. wp.io uses a third-party intermediary to manage the credit card processing. This intermediary is solely a link in the distribution chain, and is not permitted to store, retain, or use the information provided, except for the sole purpose of credit card processing. Other third parties, such as content providers, may provide content on the web Site but they are not permitted to collect any information nor does wp.io share user information with these parties.

Customers of the Service will be using the Site to host data and information (“Customer Data”). wp.io will not review, share, distribute, print, or reference any such Customer Data except as provided in the wp.io Master Subscription Agreement, or as may be required by law. Individual records may at times be viewed or accessed only for the purpose of resolving a problem, support issue, or suspected violation of the Master Subscription Agreement, or as may be required by law. Of course, customers are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and security of their user registration and password.

wp.io may also collect certain information from visitors to and customers of the Site, such as Internet addresses. This information is logged to help diagnose technical problems, and to administer our Site in order to constantly improve the quality of the Service. We may also track and analyse non-identifying and aggregate usage and volume statistical information from our visitors and customers and provide such information to third parties.  
If a user elects to use our referral service for informing a friend about our site, we ask them for the friend’s name and email address. wp.io will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting them to visit the site.

## Cookies

This site uses cookies – small text files that are placed on your machine to help the site provide a better user experience. In general, cookies are used to retain user preferences, store information for things like shopping carts, and provide anonymised tracking data to third party applications like Google Analytics.

As a rule, cookies will make your browsing experience better. However, you may prefer to disable cookies on this site and on others. The most effective way to do this is to disable cookies in your browser. We suggest consulting the Help section of your browser or taking a look at [the About Cookies website](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which offers guidance for all modern browsers.

## Third-Party Sites

The Site contains links to other web sites. wp.io is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other web sites. Customers and visitors will need to check the policy statement of these others web sites to understand their policies. Customers and visitors who access a linked site may be disclosing their private information. It is the responsibility of the user to keep such information private and confidential.

## Security

Our Site has security measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the Data under our control. When our Site is accessed using Netscape Navigator, or Microsoft Internet Explorer versions 5.5 or higher, Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology protects information using both server authentication and data encryption to help ensure that Data is safe, secure, and available only to you. wp.io provides unique user names and passwords that must be entered each time a customer logs on. These safeguards help prevent unauthorised access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the appropriate use of Data.

## Opt-Out Policy

wp.io offers its visitors and customers a means to choose how we may use information provided. If, at any time after registering for information or ordering the Service, you change your mind about receiving information from us or about sharing your information with third parties, send us a request specifying your new choice. Simply send your request to contact at wp.io.com.

## Correcting & Updating Your Information

If customers need to update or change registration information they may do so by editing the user or organisation record. To update a User Profile, log on to wp.io and select Settings to add or update information. To update billing information please email contact@wp.io.com or call +44 (0)1273 234 290. To discontinue the Service and to have data deleted, email contact at wp.io.com or call +44 (0)1273 234 290. wp.io will respond to your correction or update request within at most 30 days from the date of your request.
